

Hi, my name is

Jack Waterfall. I'm a software developer.

.languages()

- JavaScript (ES6)
- TypeScript
- Python

.frontEnd()

- React.js
- Next.is
- HTML5
- CSS3
- Styled Components
- Jest
- React-testing-library
- Cypress
- Storybook

.backEnd()

- Node.js
- Express
- MongoDB
- PostgreSQL
- GraphQl
- Firebase
- Auth0

.methodologies()

- Scrum/Agile
- Kanban
- Pair programming
- Test Driven Development

.tools()

- Github
- Jira
- Figma
- Slack
- Postman
- Docker

github.com/jwaterfall



linkedin.com/in/jwaterfall



<u>jack-waterfall.com</u>

About Me

Hi, my name is Jack waterfall and I love everything programming related! My interest in programming started back in 2012 when I was 12 years old and I decided to try creating content for various video games that I played using the LUA programming language.

I studied computer science at college where I spent 2 years learning Python and the theory of computer science. After finishing college I decided that university wasn't the correct path for me, instead I spent 3 years running a small 3D printing business, during that time I also taught myself full stack JavaScript development.

Now I want to put my skills to good use to create scalable, reliable and accessible software. I joined the School Of Code bootcamp to kickstart my career in the software development industry.

Experience

Software developer School of Code, 2021-2022

The school of code was an amazing opportunity and I am glad that I got to be a part of it. I was chosen from 1800 applicants to take part in a 16 week full time software development bootcamp. Over the course of the bootcamp I learnt lots of new skills including the fundamentals of design starting with user research, making user personas, writing user stories, wireframing my design, to creating high fidelity mock-ups using tools like Figma.

Furthermore I learnt to work as part of a team using agile methodologies such as scrum, sprints, epics and retrospectives. At the end of the course I took part in a four-week project with a team of five during which I assumed a Tech Lead role due to my prior technical experience. We worked in an agile way using Jira to plan our weekly sprints.

.hobbies()

In my spare time I enjoy cooking, I am always trying out new recipes and experimenting with food.

I also enjoy running - I love exercising in the outdoors. I have taken part in lots of of races including a couple of half marathons.

I also enjoy 3D printing. I love tinkering with printers and making things with them. I also ran a business providing printing services and selling replacement parts for 3D printers.

Our idea was to create a social media platform for developers that encourages them to collaborate on projects, it combines features from existing applications such as Facebook, Slack and Stack Overflow into one central place. Users would be able to make posts and include code snippets. This feature could be used to share personal experiences, useful code snippets or to ask questions for other users to answer. There is also a chat and groups feature to encourage users to collaborate with each other. Our app would also give you a list of recommended contacts who shared similar interests and were open to collaborate on a project.

At the end of the 4 weeks we presented our project to a panel of judges who work in the software development industry. This project not only helped to improve my teamworking skills, along the way I learned how to use tools such as Jira and Git to effectively manage the project.

Freelance software developer 2018-2021

After finishing college I decided that I wanted to learn software development so I spent 3 years running my own business, during this time I taught myself full stack JavaScript development.

I learnt technologies such as TypeScript React.js, Node.js, Next.js, Express and MongoDB in order to build full stack applications. Alongside learning these technologies I took on several small freelance jobs for different clients. One of these jobs was to build a blockchain explorer for a cryptocurrency coin.

I also helped develop a cryptocurrency coin of my own, I built a custom blockchain explorer and a sportsbook website centred around this coin.

Education

Student

Derby College, 2016-2018

At college I studied computer science, maths and physics. As part of my computer science course I learnt the Python programming language and advanced programming concepts such as object oriented programming recursion. I learnt computer science theory including topics such as binary and hexadecimal number systems, computer architecture and the fundamentals of networking.

I also learnt how to take a systematic approach to problem solving using computational thinking.

Check out my portfolio for examples of my work.

jack-waterfall.com